Leonard van Riel

Full-Stack Web Developer

Portfolio: https://selectyes.github.io/portfolio/

Location: Hermanus **Mobile:** 081 387 9603

WhatsApp: +57 310 7618144 Email: riel lenny@yahoo.co.uk

PERSONAL PROFILE

With a background in electrical engineering and as a home-network / AV technician, I feel at home in an ever-changing technical environment. My curiosity naturally led me to explore the realm of programming. Fascinated by the possibilities of software development, I devoured countless online sources to learn more. Through building software solutions for clients and myself, I have gained a solid understanding of the intricacies of the web development ecosystem, readily absorbing new frameworks and languages and striving for robust code and flawless user experiences.

Please take a look at my web developer portfolio.

OBJECTIVE

To secure a position in a professional environment, challenge myself, expand my knowledge and abilities and utilise my skills as a software developer, building websites and/or applications. It is important for me to learn the intricacies of working with a development team to contribute to the growth of the company and to advance in my career as a passionate web developer.

EDUCATION

The British Council | Hanoi, Vietnam - Certificate IELTS Practical Teaching Methodology

2017

i-to-i | Cape Town, South Africa - Certificate TEFL Teaching Qualification

2014

Campus of Performing Arts | Cape Town, South Africa -Diploma Musical Performing Arts (Guitar)

2013

Boland College | Western Cape - Diploma Electrical Engineering

2007

SKILLS

Javascript

HTML

CSS/SCSS

React

Git & Github

Node.JS

ONLINE SOFTWARE DEV COURSES

The Complete Javascript Course Jonas Schmedtman (65 hours)

The Web Developer Bootcamp Colt Steele (62 hours)

Advanced CSS and Sass Jonas Schmedtman (28 hours)

Responsive Web Design Certification Free Code Camp (300 hours)

Complete React Developer Andrei Neagoie (41 hours)

Web Design for Web Developers Jonas Schmedtman (3 hours)

Master Wordpress Andrew Williams (9 hours)

EXPERIENCE

Likeshuo | Remote - English Language Teacher

2018 - PRESENT

Teaching English via an online platform, focusing on conversational fluency, grammar, vocabulary and pronunciation (levels A1–C2). Evaluation of student performance, providing constructive feedback.

GLN | Hanoi, Vietnam - English Language Teacher

2017 - 2018

Teaching learners from teens to adults, including Summer programme.

American Academy | Hanoi, Vietnam - English Language Teacher

2016 - 2018

Developing speaking, listening and grammar, with a philosophy of learning through fun, engaging activities.

Singapore Helm Institute of Education | Siem Reap, Cambodia - Elementary Classroom / Adult ESL Teacher

2014 - 2015

Daytime, teaching ages 9-11. Evenings, conducting adult conversational lessons at beginner-intermediate level.

Self Employed | Dubai / South Africa - Musician / Music Tutor

2011 - 2014

In 2011, I decided to pursue a career in music performance. I formed a cover band and after a couple of months of playing at various venues, from your everyday bar venues to corporate functions, we landed a contract to perform as house band at The Metropolitan Hotel in Dubai. Upon our return, I decided to study for a diploma in contemporary music at The Campus of Performing Arts. During this time, I offered private guitar tutoring and continued to build experience as a performing artist.

Chameleon Technologies | Somerset West, South Africa - AV Systems & Home Network Technician / Installer

2010 - 2011

Installing / maintaining AV systems and home networks with a small team of professional technicians.

Hermanus Electrical | Hermanus, South Africa - Electrical Engineer

2007 - 2010

Responsibilities ranged from call-outs to clients' houses for maintenance jobs to meeting with architects / builders to schedule work and leading small teams on construction sites.

LANGUAGES English, Afrikaans

INTERESTS Music, Health & Fitness, Programming, Video Games